Andrew Galloway

ajgalloway.github.io ajgalloway97@gmail.com | +1.570.439.8802 405 Broad St. FL 2, Montoursville, PA 17754

EDUCATION

MCNEESE STATE UNIVERSITY B.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE &

B.S IN MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES Aug 2015 - Dec 2019 | Lake Charles, LA

LINKS

Github://ajgalloway LinkedIn://ajgalloway

COURSEWORK

UNDERGRADUATE

Data Structures & Algorithms
Database Systems
Object Oriented Programming
Computer Organization & Architecture
Structures of Programming Languages
Operating Systems
Artificial Intelligence
(Research Asst. & Teaching Asst.)

SKILLS

Proficient:

Python • JavaScript • Java

- Node Django Spring Intermediate:
- C Android HTML CSS
- PostgreSQL Git

Familiar:

React • Matlab • MySQL

- MongoDB ATFX Unity
- AWS

ORGANIZATIONS

- Member of McNeese ACM (2017-2019)
- National Member of ACM (2018-2020)
- Participated in the Southeast regional ICPC (2017-2019)
- Member of the National Society for Leadership & Success since 2016

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack software engineer, with several years of experience developing software systems. My most recent work has been in the eCommerce and logistics industry. Aside from being a team player, I have had the chance to lead product teams as a developer and function as a project manager, utilizing agile methodologies. I enjoy continuous learning in many forms from building upon academic foundations and expanding my professional portfolio to attaining new personal skills. I am always interested in adapting to and learning from a new challenge.

EXPERIENCE

GOPHR APP INC | Full-Stack Software Engineer

May 2019 - Present | Lake Charle, LA

- Reduced project overhead by utilizing AWS cloud infrastructure.
- Deployed fully functional Node applications ahead of schedule.
- Improved long-term system scalability by utilizing a micro-service architecture
- Empowered stakeholder decision making by maintaining BI tools.
- Led multiple project teams utilizing agile methodologies.

CGI FEDERAL | DEVOPS ENGINEERING INTERN

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 | Lafayette, LA

- Reduced disaster recover time by testing and improving project documentation.
- Deployed, maintained, and documented an internal retrospective tool.
- Participated in SCRUM framework and related ceremonies.
- Worked within a diverse team of peers.

MCNEESE STATE UNIVERSITY | TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019 | Lake Charles, LA

- Communicated concepts to individuals at various stages of their career.
- Critiqued and graded programming projects and papers.
- Lectured on a range of Computer Science classes.
- Assisted students with projects and labs.
- Researched and prepared related documents on specific topics.

360FUEL | Full-Stack Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Mar 2019 | Lake Charles, LA

- Led development teams that utilized agile methodologies.
- Launched the company's first product.
- Deployed and developed internal and external Android applications.
- Published the initial 360Fuel app on the Google Play Store.

RESEARCH

MCNEESE LAACES PROGRAM | STUDENT RESEARCHER

Sep 2017 - May 2019 | Lake Charles, LA

- Worked with a multi-discipline team of engineering students.
- Developed a long-range communication system, and a mobile GPS tracking system consisting of a payload and ground station.
- Successfully delivered, launched, and recovered our payload.

(The Louisiana Aerospace Catalysts Experiences for Students (LaACES) is a student ballooning program, sponsored by NASA, consisting of a consortium of Louisiana universities.)